Contact

cnh299@nyu.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/chrisnhsiao (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership
Project Management
Time Management

Certifications

Basic Life Support (BLS) Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

2019-2020 Overall Distinguished Traditional Baccalaureate Student Louis and Rachel Rudin Foundation Nursing Scholarship Global Pathways Scholarship Dean's List

Publications

Transformational leadership: Florence Nightingale's legacy

Chris Hsiao, BS, RN

Newly graduated Registered Nurse with an interest in critical care New York

Summary

I am an NYU alum who graduated with a BS in Nursing and Global Public Health in May 2020. I am interested in critical care and research and am excited to use what I learned at NYU Meyers into practice. My clinical experience gifted me the opportunity to work at some of NYC's top hospitals, like New York-Presbyterian and NYU Langone Tisch. Outside of nursing, I love playing volleyball and the piano. I am also passionate about cooking and volunteering.

Experience

New York University 2 years 10 months

Hartford Institute Geriatric Undergraduate Scholar (HIGUS) September 2019 - May 2020 (9 months)

I researched factors that lead to a decreased amount of suicide assessments among the elderly (65+) primarily in the emergency room and in the primary care setting.

Resident Assistant

January 2018 - May 2020 (2 years 5 months)

New York, United States

I directly supported 54 first-year students with needs related to residential life and overall healthy living. I organized different events, ranging from community building to cultural exposure in London and New York City. While being on call for periods of 8-24 hours, I was also responsible to manage various crises and enforce the university's policy.

Cohort Leader

August 2017 - May 2018 (10 months)

New York City, NY

I conducted biweekly seminars with an advisor and students of the Class of 2021 and organized various outings to expose first-year nursing students to life in NYU, NYC, and nursing as a profession.

NYU School of Medicine, Center for Health Informatics and Bioinformatics
Research Assistant
September 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 1 month)
New York, United States

In this study, we were tasked to learn about the second and third-hand effects of E-cigarettes and hookah to family members. I performed cardiopulmonary tests and air sampling analysis while evaluating and documenting data into SPSS statistics program.

NYU Langone Health Summer Nurse Extern June 2019 - August 2019 (3 months) New York, United States

Working on a post-surgical primary for bariatrics and plastics, secondary for vascular and orthopedic spine, I had the opportunity to collaborate with an interdisciplinary team to perform patient care under an RN preceptor. I worked towards refining nursing skills like assessing patients and creating care plans alongside a preceptor.

Kaiser Permanente UCLA Cope Health Scholar May 2018 - August 2018 (4 months) Los Angeles, California, United States

I rotated through a medical-surgical unit, orthopedic/podiatry unit, urology unit, and a family practice office. I delivered patient-centered care at the bedside & operating rooms using AIDET techniques. Through this role, I served as assistive personnel by setting up sterile fields, taking vital signs, and other such tasks.

Asher Levy Elementary School & Tompkins Square Middle School Teacher's Assistant
September 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 4 months)
New York, NY

I taught 7th-graders and 4th graders 1-on-1 and would also teach the lesson plan alongside their teachers. I assisted students with classwork and would help with grading homework and exams.

Dr. Raymond Li Doctor's Assistant June 2010 - June 2016 (6 years 1 month) Page 2 of 3

Torrance, CA

I integrated patient files and labs from paper copies to an electrical medical record at a primary care office to help with the accessibility of receiving ones medical information.

Education

NYU Rory Meyers College of Nursing

Bachelor of Science - BS, Nursing · (2016 - 2020)

NYU School of Global Public Health
Bachelor's degree, Global Public Health · (2016 - 2020)